Shehroz Kaleem

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan



me@shehroz.pk



03335371083



linkedin.com/in/shehrozkaleem

Summary

I'm an ambitious procurement specialist, having more than 5 years of experience in sourcing and buying good quality products and acquiring dependable services by the most feasible means.

I look forward to joining a world-class & forward-thinking organization for my next aspiring role.

Experience



Procurement Executive

Al-Jalil Garden

Jun 2021 - Present (5 months +)

Manage procurement for 3 Housing Projects under CCTV Surveillance, Networking, IT, Machinery, Plumbing and Housekeeping categories.

Technical Purchaser

The Knights

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020 (3 months)

- Managed IT purchases for 2 office locations impacting 160+ personnel
- Formulated the company's purchase policy and SOP for the first time
- Helped in the deployment of TimeTrax HR management system
- Setup the company's IT asset storage & testing facility for the first time
- Reduced up to 30% IT OPEX utilizing internal controls on procurement
- · Harvested written off IT assets and reused them, which in turn led up to 25% reduction in CAPEX
- Served as a Single Point of contact for all IT related matters
- Deployed and relocated more than 60% of all IT assets to new offices with complementary troubleshooting
- On-boarded several source suppliers to supplement the vendor pool
- Spot buying computer hardware and parts from Rawalpindi & Islamabad markets
- I did product sourcing, RFQ, vendor onboarding, PO, PRF handling, inventory receipt and issuance
- Managed the whole P2P cycle for the IT department

Procurement Officer

Hag's International

Oct 2015 - Aug 2020 (4 years 11 months)

- Rejuvenated the entire procurement function
- Implemented state-of-the-art iPOS ERP system and entered data from scratch for FBR POS integration project
- Led buying supplies from 70+ vendors and 9000+ items in real time
- Carried out monthly internal Procurement audit and reporting

- Prepared monthly sales tax return' Annex A for input tax, cross-compilation, verification, coordination with suppliers & tax consultant
- Withheld income tax from vendor invoices & prepared tax challans
- · Did cost evaluation analysis and invoice cross verification with procurement contracts and agreed price lists
- · Processed vendor invoices and approved payments
- Executed vendor relationship management & contract administration
- · Inventory receipt, inspection, storage and issuance
- Supervised 4 direct reporting employees

Education



WI Virtual University of Pakistan

Bachelors in Business Administration

Skills

Demand assessment • Negotiation • Cost Reduction • Sourcing • Communication • Procurement • Quotations • Strategic Planning • Capex • English